我还以为他要出去吃早餐呢
Ithought he was supposed to have a breakfast date, right?
我是说 他们昨晚是这么和我说的
I mean, they told me that last night.
早餐? 排在档期上吗
Breakfast? Is that on the sched?
没 但是警督是这么告诉我的
It isn't, but the lieutenant told me
说他要去港口那里同什么人吃早饭
that he'd be doing breakfast with someone down at the harbor.
我是说 如果他不去
I mean, if he ain't,
我就可以去Fallsway加油了
I could go get this gassed up at the Fallsway.
我真不想听这些 兄弟
I hate this detail, man.
这是下班时间嘛 有津贴的
It's off duty. Lotsa perks.
站在这里干等的感觉 你知道么
All this stand around and wait, you know?
Hoskins说我这么干一年
Hoskins says I do the one year,
明年升警司的名单里就有我
and I'll make sergeant on the next list.
对 他们告诉我 这是职场智慧
Yeah. They told me, careerwise,
有什么比给市长开车更好的差事呢
you can't do better than drive the mayor.
唉 如果按照正常那么升职
Shit, if you could make rank the right way,
我还在西巴尔的摩毒检局呢
I'll still be working Western drugs.
好吧 我不管了
All right, fuck this,
我进去找警督
I'm gonna go look for the lieutenant.
要是有人查岗
Anyone comes looking,
就说我在二楼
I'm back up on the second floor.
先生
Sir?
有人告诉我说市长
I understood that the mayor
要去港口那儿吃早餐?
might be going to, uh, breakfast at the harbor?
和Kweisi一起
With Kweisi.
但我想这事是吹了
But, um, that's up in the air, I thought.
那您知不知道Hoskins警长在哪儿吗
Would you happen to know where Lieutenant Hoskins is?
老大?
Sir?
警督
Lieutenant:
火线重案组 第四季 第2集
The.Wire.S04E02
* When you walk through the garden *
* Watch your back *
* Well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* If you walk with Jesus *
* Save your soul *
* Gotta keep the devil *
* Down in the hole *
* He's got the fire and the fury *
* At his command *
* Well you don't have to worry *
* Hold on to Jesus hand *
* We'll all be safe from Satan *
* When the thunder rolls *
* But you gotta keep the devil *
* Down in the hole *
* We'll all be safe from Satan *
* Gotta keep the devil *
* Down in the hole *
* Keep the devil *
* Keep them in the hole *
* Down in the hole *
我却依然以白人的身份 苏醒于一个黑人城市中 —— Carcetti
你看上去不开心啊 警探
You don't look happy, Detective.
我们这是要惩凶除恶了
We're about to raise some hell.
也许是动静太大了点了
Maybe too much hell.
一位参议员 两位众议员
A state senator, two councilmen,
城市发展院
the City Development Agency,
所有的开发商
all those developers...
城中王侯们
Princes of the city.
Lester 告诉我你完全没有想过
Lester, tell me the thought hasn't
会有什么脏水
crossed your mind that some kinda shit
朝我们这儿泼 老兄
could blow back on us, man.
你知道罗斯福是怎么说
Do you know what Theodore Roosevelt said
捕猎灰熊的感觉的吗
about hunting grizzly bears?
精彩的是战胜自身的恐惧
The thrill is in overcoming your own fear.
那对熊有什么好精彩的
What was the thrill for the bear?
我应该在负责人办公室里
I should've run every one of these subpoenas
就把传票一张张看一遍
by my front office.
程序不是这么走的
That's not procedure.
去他妈的程序 Lester
Fuck procedure, Lester.
我老板有了市长的支持
My boss is running two points behind
还在选举中落后两个点
in the polls with the mayor's support.
你觉得万一他惹恼了Royce
How do you think he's gonna do
并且在选举中支持率下降
if he pisses off Royce
他会怎么做呢
and starts dropping off incumbent tickets?
关你什么事
Why do you care?
要是Demper觉得我背地里阴了他 然后他又赢下了选举
If Demper thinks I fucked him and he wins,
我会去中央登记处负责登记保释
I will be at Central Booking covering bail reviews.
要是他输给了Bond
If he loses to Bond,
新的管理班子入主 他们说不定觉得
a new front office comes in and maybe they bounce
得把白人姑娘踢回诉讼组
the white girl back to a trial team
然后把毒品组交给自己人打理
and give the Narcotics Division to one of their own.
这儿是巴尔的摩啊 Lester
It's Baltimore, Lester.
少了几张传票
We're missing a couple of subpoenas.
有吗
We are?
Clay Davis和Andy Krawczyk的
Clay Davis and Andy Krawczyk.
留着10月传唤
I'm holding those till October.
搞什么呢你
Oh, the hell you are.
Lester...
我们在大选前三周
we drop subpoenas on either of those guys
传唤这其中的任何一个
three weeks before the primary,
我们就等着失业吧
and all hell breaks loose.
我就是这意思
That's what I'm sayin'!
Clay Davis是Royce的竞选委员会副主席
Clay Davis is Royce's deputy campaign chairman,
而且是市立法委的二号人物
and the number-two man at the City Legislative Caucus.
而Krawczyk又是头号的基金募集人
And Krawczyk is his number-one fundraiser!
甭给我介绍建立和名号了
You're giving me resumes and job titles.
我只追着赃款
I'm just following the money.
会追查的 等选举结束
And we will follow it... after the polls close.
我们可以到时候再传唤
We can drop a second batch of subpoenas.
没必要现在冒险...
There is no reason to do this now and risk--
一年前 如果我们追查这些记录
A year ago, if we had gone after these records,
市政厅会狠狠地把我们小组
City Hall would've stomped on this unit
还有这些传票都打压下去
and the subpoenas.
过一个月 等Royce连任了
And a month from now, after Royce is reelected,
他们还会这么对待我们
they'll do us the same way.
但现在 马上要大选了
But right now, with the primary coming,
他们担心的是自己的光鲜外表
they gotta worry about how they look,
表现够不够好
how they behave.
现在 他们得担心会不会有丑闻
Right now, they gotta worry about scandal.
你告诉我你一年前就想办这案子了
You told me you wanted to do this a year ago,
但新案子太多忙不过来
but fresh cases got in the way.
你当初是这么说来着
You told me that.
哦
Oh.
真聪明 Lester
Very clever, Lester.
你全都算计好了 是不
You got it all figured, huh?
我吗
Me...
我不过是个警察
I'm just the police.
教师协会最后还是支持了Royce
I saw the teachers' union finally endorsed Royce.
你知道他们早晚会这么做的
You knew they were gonna.
你第一次露面是什么时候
What time's your first appearance?
今天吗
Today?
我会跟你们在SoWeBo论坛碰头
I meet up with you guys at the SoWeBo forum.
然后今晚带着孩子站在Tommy身边
And tonight, it's me and the kids next to Tommy
参加Roland公园基金募集会
at the Roland Park fundraiser.
我去催催他吧
Better speed things along.
踹他一脚挺管用的
A kick in the ass sometimes helps.
- 不 爸爸 D-5
- B-5? - B-5? - No, Daddy, D-5.
你确定你刚说的不是B-5吗
You sure you didn't say B-5?
D-5 我打中什么了?
D-5. What did I hit?
潜水艇
Submarine.
嗯...
Umm...
E-6
E-6.
没打中
Miss.
再给我10分钟
Just gimme 10 minutes.
你今天没看日程安排吗
You seen your schedule today?
10分钟也不行
You ain't got 10 minutes.
Norman 我差点就能
Norman, I got this pretty girl's
把这小萌妹的航空母舰给搞定了
aircraft carrier boxed in.
- 哦! 打中了
- D-4 - D-4. - Ow! Hit.
Tommy 别闹了
Tommy, for Christ's sakes.
我还有机会赢吗
Is there any way that I can win?
以他们现在的支持率 我还有可能吗
With the numbers what they are, is there any way at all?
没错 如果只是要坚持到底的话
Right, so if it's just a matter of playing out the string,
我也会坚持的
then that's what I'm gonna do.
但那场比赛基本算是结束了 Norman
That game's pretty much over, Norman.
而这场比赛 这儿的比赛
But this game-- this game right here--
还没有决出胜负
this one could still go either way.
H-11 亲爱的
H-11, sweetheart.
没打中 D-3
Miss. D-3.
我想你们都拿到需要的东西了吧
So I guess y'all getting what y'all need?
- Brianna同你们亲密吗 - 她说到做到
- Brianna keepin' y'all close? - She come up with it.
每个月都如约送钱来
Money comin' through every month like she say.
好吧 因为我在这儿还坚持得下去
A'ight, 'cause I'm standin' tall up in here.
他们不需要担心我
They don't need to worry about me
我也不需要担心他们
an' I ain't need to worry about them.
- 你是个士兵 Bey - 你知道的
- You a soldier, Bey. - You know it.
我的鱼还好么
Everything all right with my fishes?
你告诉我它们都还好吧
You'd tell me if it wasn't, right?
鱼都好 我是说 它们是鱼
The fish be fine. I mean, they fish, right?
我咋知道它们乐不乐
How I know how they feelin' about shit?
- 鱼都好 Bey
- De'londa... - De'londa... - They fine, Bey.
你问Namond
Ask Namond.
一直按你说的清洗鱼缸
Cleaned the tank an' all, like you say.
- 还有过滤器 - 好吧 好吧
- Cleaned the filter, too. - A'ight, a'ight.
就是问问呢
Check you out, though.
上面起了一点毛了哈
Getting some fuzz up there, huh?
- 嗯嗯 - 对
- Mm-hmm. - Yeah, whatever.
我自己还是个楞头青的时候 儿子
I know when I was a little kid, boy,
等不及想要刮胡子啊
I couldn't wait till I started shaving.
街角有个老混混说
One of the old heads on the corner say,
"嘿 小子 想要留胡子么"
"Hey, little man, you wanna grow a 'stache?
下次你生气的时候
Next time you take a piss,
记得要这样
take some of that piss,
拿手指摸一摸
get it on your fingertips,
好像这个样子
do like this, here."
哇 你真这么干了
Eww! You do it:
没错我真这么干了
You damn right I did it.
操
Shit.
你怎么样 儿子
What's going on with you, though, son?
没啥 快开学了
Ain't nothing. School about to start.
那Bodie和他的跟班呢
So what about Bodie and his boys?
他们对你还好吗
They treatin' you right?
对 还行
Yeah, he cool.
儿子 别对你父亲撒谎
Boy, don't lie to your father.
他大半时间都没有去上班
He don't even show up for work half the damn time.
- Bodie告诉我的 - 我少去了几天 仅此而已 老爸
- Bodie told me. - I missed a few days. That's all, Dad.
还有你赚的钱
And what money you do make,
全都浪费了
you waste on nonsense.
你要是觉得我会掏钱
And if you think I'm gonna give you a dime
给你买开学新衣服 你就别做梦了
for your school clothes, you better think again.
Bodie让你做什么了
What Bodie got you doin'?
大多数时间是让我送货
I'm a runner, most days.
起步都是这样的
Everybody got to start somewhere.
你好好听你父亲的话
You better listen to your father.
他没说你这头发吗
He ain't tell you 'bout that hair, though, huh?
有 他说我得去剪了
Yeah, he said I gotta get it cut.
我喜欢这样
I like it this way.
哪怕是一个白人警察
Even the white police lookin' out from
从三个街区外看过来
three blocks away gonna be able to spot you
都能把你同其他黑人分辨出来
from every other nigga out there.
他们会说"瞧瞧那边那个小子
They gonna hop out and say, "Look at the boy over there
扎傻逼马尾辫的那个 抓住他"
with the pretty-ass ponytail. Get him."
你觉得我是在胡扯
You think I'm bullshitting.
你在外面要么懂事 要么就混不下去
Either you real out there, or you ain't, Nay.
你懂我的意思么
You see what I'm sayin'?
给我点!
Let me get some!
嘿 你!过来!
Hey, yo! Over here!
- 哇! 100刀 - 谢谢 先生!
- Whoa! $100! - Thanks, mister!
- 谢谢 Marlo先生! - 谢谢!
- Thank you, Mr. Marlo! - Thank you!
那是我的钱 喂
That's my money, yo!
你一定声名远扬了 老兄
Your name gonna ring out, man.
Manuel... （西班牙语)
Manuel...
小子 你说这话比我强
Boy, you talk that shit better'n me
我已经同那些墨西哥人 打了好几年交道
and I been dealin' with these Mexicans for years now.
对 我觉得他们不会
Yeah, I don't think they would call
把我说的话叫做西班牙语 兄弟
what I'm speakin' Spanish, man.
就是随口吐几句脏
Just a dirty word or two here or there.
对 但你一旦同这些猫儿搭上话了
Yeah, well. Once you can talk to these cats,
你就只需要再来一辆卡车就行了
the only thing you need then is a truck, man.
可以自己搞一队人
Could be runnin' your own crew,
接一点新的客户
pickin' up fresh clients.
我是说 如果我们合作
I mean, if we put in together
我们可以扩张两倍的地盘
we could be coverin' twice the ground,
赚两倍的钱
makin' twice as much.
不了 兄弟 我还有其他的事要做
Nah, man, I got other obligations.
哦 好吧
Oh, right.
你可是要做新Angelo Dundee的 （传奇拳击教练)
You set to be the new Angelo Dundee.
我差点忘了
I near forgot.
我还以为你去了Mondawmin
I thought you already went up
去买开学的东西了
to Mondawmin to get your school shit, man.
对 但也不全是
Yeah, but not all of it.
还有我兄弟
And my boy,
得自己付学费
he need to pay for his own shit
还有他弟弟的也是
and his little brother, too.
这儿他妈的看上去
The fuck this look like,
难道向社区服务站吗
a Social Services office?
你要钱 就去找Rosemont
You want a check, go the fuck up Rosemont.
别这样 兄弟 我会努力工作的
Come on, man, I'll work for it.
不行 我带着你只是因为你爸
Nay, I took you on outta respect for your father,
懂么 但我不能
a'ight, but I can't go hirin'
把这个社区的人都雇下来
the whole damn neighborhood.
你就替我工作吧
You can have my job until
直到赚够你和Bug的学费为止
you get enough for you an' Bug.
- 谢了 - 好吧 你们没意见 我就无所谓
- Thanks, man. - Yeah, work for y'all, work for me, yo.
警察来了 滚远点
Po-po. Step the fuck off.
来找你小弟Lex的
Looking for your man Lex.
我瞧见他的扫把 但没瞧见他
I see his broom, but I don't see him.
你的二把手去哪儿了
Where's your number two been at?
- 我也没见过他 - 啥时候的事?
- I ain't seen him. - Since when?
我还以为我们说好了呢
I thought we were on better terms.
还是你希望我每隔15分钟
Or do you want me rolling past
就来找一次Lex?
Iookin' for Lex every 15 minutes?
他要是来 我会打电话给你的
He come past, I'll call you.
真的!
I will!
如果他来的话
If he come past.
哦 不 我不知道
Oh no, I don't know.
他们使出浑身解数呢
They're spinning their wheels.
你知道的 可怜的Tony Gray
You know, poor Tony Gray,
拿到了20%的黑人选票
pulling 20% of the black vote.
真尴尬
It's embarrassing.
谁他妈知道
Well, who knows what the fuck
Carcetti想要证明什么呢
Carcetti's trying to prove?
但我得告诉你 等这事儿结束了
But I tell you, at the end of this thing,
他保准后悔没站在我这边
he's gonna regret getting on the wrong side of me.
嗯嗯
Mm-hmm.
好了 我这儿有你需要的东西 孩子
A'ight, now. I got what you need, boy,
干净的T恤 什么码的都有
clean tees, any sizes, huh?
要买袜子 内裤
Lookin' for socks, briefs,
还是骰子 打火机 纸牌
you lookin' for dice, Zippos, cards--
请到移动市场来买吧
come on over to the Rollin' Emporium.
你不来找Rite-Aid
You ain't gotta walk to Rite-Aid.
Rite-Aid也会来找你们
Shit, Rite-Aid comin' to y'all.
需要什么 亲爱的
What can I get you, baby?
干净的骰子 再来一包Trojans
Fresh dice an' a pack of Trojans.
- 好的 - 有Philly Blunts吗
- All righty. - You got Philly Blunts, too?
我这儿什么都有
Bubbles got it all, dawg.
我们是一站式购物
I'm the one-stop shop.
- 多少钱 - 6块多
- How much is that? - Six an' a bit.
谢谢 非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you kindly.
对 先生 我知道你在看什么
Yes, sir, I see what you're lookin' at.
两块钱一副牌 明码标价
Two a deck, name brand.
谢绝还价
You can't beat that price.
给我两副牌
Yeah, let me get two decks, man,
还要件白T恤 XX号的
and a white tee, double-X.
再给我点喷漆
And give me the rest of them paint cans, too, man.
好的 好的 给 多少?
All right, all right, there you go. That's it?
对 多少?
Yeah, what's that?
他应该付多少钱 Sherrod?
How much the man owe, Sherrod?
- 13块 - 哇 哇 哇
- 13. - Whoa whoa whoa.
他是把喷漆全要了
He asked for all the cans.
三罐是12块 还有其他的东西
Three cans is $12, plus the other stuff.
是19块 19块 先生
It's $19. $19, sir.
拜托 这还是跳楼价啊
Come on, you still gettin' off with a deal,
你不必跑老远去买
Now, you didn't have to move your feet.
是我们来找你的 对么
We came to you, right?
我的错 19块 按他说的
My bad. $19, like he said.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
他是个实习生 我在带他
He's an intern, I'm working with him.
但是 夫人 我问的是
But, ma'am, what I'm asking is
你最后一次看到Lex是什么时候
when was the last time you saw Lex?
哦 抱歉 Curtis?
Oh, excuse me-- Curtis?
嗯
Hmm.
- 两天前吗 - 我不知道他去哪儿了
- Two days ago? - I don't know where he at.
三天前
Three days?
介意我看一看么
You mind if I look around?
我更希望你离开我家
I'd rather you leave my house be.
Anderson夫人
Well, Ms. Anderson...
你的儿子惹麻烦了
your son is in trouble,
我知道你很不自在
and I can tell you're upset.
但你能为他做的最好的事情
But the best thing that you can do for him--
他能为自己做的最好的事情
the best thing that he can do for himself--
就是跟我谈谈
is talk to me.
我实话告诉你吧
I'm gonna tell you the truth:
我们知道他在贩毒
We know he's selling drugs.
而我也要告诉你
And I'm gonna tell you...
我什么都不知道
I don't know nothin' about that.
但我要说的是 我才不管
But I'm telling you that I don't care
他是不是贩毒
he's selling drugs.
跟我一点关系都没
I'm not even gonna bother with that.
我来这儿 是因为一起谋杀
I'm here because of a homicide,
现在的情况是
and the way it looks right now
那场谋杀之后
your boy is running from the police
你儿子正在躲避警察
behind that killing.
我不知道他在哪儿
I don't know where he at...
夫人
Ma'am...
议员 我的人手四年来拿的工资
Councilman, my people got only
不过糊口而已
cost-of-living bumps for four years.
士气更是低落
Morale is at rock bottom.
要是情况都一样 我们会选你
All things being equal, you'd be our guy.
我们喜欢你所说的
We like what we hear.
但现在的支持率显示Royce会赢
The polls say it's going to be Royce.
要是我们支持你 最后可能没好结果
We endorse you now, we're out in the cold.
Bobby 也许这是一个打下
Bobby... this might be the chance to get in on
更好未来的根基的大好机会
the ground floor of something better.
也许是没错 警司长 但现在
That may be true, Major. But for now,
我们只能见机行事
we're gonna play the cards that we were dealt.
- 议员 如果你是我 - 我保证
Councilman, if you were me, I'm sure--
我会明哲保身 同教师
I'd cover my ass and endorse Royce,
及消防队员一起支持Royce
along with the teachers and the firefighters.
但我也告诉我的成员们
But I'd also tell my membership
不要因此受到影响 因为
not to get carried away. I mean,
警察公会是否支持Royce
it's one thing for the police union
是一码事
to call out for Royce,
而全体下了班的警察
it's another thing entirely for off-duty cops
去给市长接电话拉票
to be manning the mayor's phone banks
又是另一码事了
and polling stations.
我觉得我手下的警员
I don't think any of my officers
对任何一位候选人都不会 表现得过于支持
will be too aggressive for anybody.
这点我可以保证
That much I can give you.
你尽力了 Tommy
Best you could do, Tommy.
Royce把这群傻瓜都吓坏了
Royce has got all those fucks runnin' scared.
对
Yeah...
我尽力了
best I could do.
今晚表现不错 Tommy
Call it a night, Tommy.
你明天还要准备辩论
You got a debate to prepare for tomorrow.
对 辩论
Yeah. Debate.
这个节骨眼上没什么比这更重要了
Nothing matters more at this point.
你就大胆实话实说吧 Norman
Let the truth set you free, Norman.
啥事都不重要了
Nothing matters at all.
谢了
Thanks.
来啊 小子 来
Come on, boy, come on now.
兄弟 你最好别累坏了
Man, you better not be getting tired,
因为你周六晚上
'cause you gonna get put to the test
- 还要考试 - 我准备好了
- on Saturday night. - I'm ready.
- 嘿 Johnson小姐 - 嘿 Justin 你好 Dennis
- Hey, Miss Johnson. - Hey, Justin. Hello, Dennis.
你是Spider的妈妈 对吗
You're Spider's mother, right?
对 Sharon  Sharon Johnson
Right, Sharon. Sharon Johnson.
你儿子走了一会儿了
Your boy left here a while ago.
我不是来找他的
I ain't looking for him.
他在他奶奶家
He at his grandmother's.
我想来问你件事情
I wanted to ask you something.
你知道 我儿子崇拜死你了
You know, my son is crazy about you.
他张口闭口都是拳击 要去健身馆
All he talks about is boxing, bein' at the gym,
还有教练都教了他什么
and what his coach been teachin' him.
Spider是个好孩子
Well, Spider's a good kid.
他十分有体育天赋
He really studies the sport.
Dennis 我很感激你你对Spider的教育
Dennis, I am so grateful for your interest in Spider,
我想给你做顿晚饭
I want to cook you dinner.
今晚如何
How 'bout tonight?
啊 谢谢你 Sharon
Well, ah, that is really nice, Sharon.
但是周末有四个男孩要去比赛
But the thing is, I got four of my boys fighting this weekend,
我得好好训练他们
and I got to train 'em really hard
这几天晚上都是
these next few evenings.
你每天晚上都在这里
You in here every night of the week.
你也不去寻寻乐子么
What you do for fun?
比如 你总得吃饭 对吗
Look here, you got to eat, right?
你看着我就知道
And you can look at me and know
我下厨是很在行的
I throw down in the kitchen--
其他地方也是
among other places.
对 这样吧
Yeah, I tell you what:
你给我做一盘菜 带过来
If you fix me up a plate and bring it over here,
那就再好不过了
I would love that.
行
That I can do.
- 他说什么 - "我吗 我不过是个警察"
- He said what? - "Me? I'm just the police."
口气再轻松不过了
Like butter wouldn't melt in his mouth.
我最气不过的是
And the thing that I resent most
他不光是在玩弄系统
is that he's not just playing the system,
他是在玩弄我
he's playing me.
好像我也是问题的一部分一样
Like I'm part of the problem.
你是想把Davis和Krawczyk的文件
You were gonna hold back the paper
都压住 对吗
for Davis and Krawczyk, right?
压到大选结束
Only until the primary was over.
但是你现在却有罪恶感
And now you feel guilty about it.
他那么说的时候
Did he do that thing where he, uh,
他有没有从眼镜的上面瞥你?
stares at you over the top of his reading glasses?
要知道 那个表情表示
You know, that look that says,
"我把你当女儿
"I'm the father you never had,
我不想再对你失望"
and I don't want to be disappointed in you ever again."
一点都不好笑 Cedric!
It's not funny, Cedric!
那些传票今天就发出去了!
Those subpoenas went out today!
管理班子那儿要炸开了!
The front office is gonna go batshit!
但你还是这么做了
But you did it anyway.
抱歉 但是 靠 我很高兴
I'm sorry, but shit, I'm just glad to see
见到Lester是对付别人 而不是我
Lester doing it to somebody other than me.
嘿 你这是拖累我们 Sherrod
Hey, you holdin' us back, Sherrod.
我算错了 你大惊小怪什么呢
I made a mistake, man. Why you trippin'?
如果我能放你去收钱
If I can cut you loose to handle the money,
我们的销售面就可以是现在的两倍
we can cover twice the ground,
卖掉两倍的商品
selling twice the merchandise.
更多的...怎么说来着
More-- more-- what you call it,
市场份额
uh, market share.
但现在我却得看牢你
Instead I gotta keep your ass close.
你本该自己推着车去卖了
You shoulda been promoted to your own cart by now.
但你现在却四处碰壁
You keep on hittin' your dome on the glass ceiling.
- 碰什么? - 你得加强数学锻炼
- Glass what? - You gotta step up the math skills
如果你还想在这行发展下去
if you wanna advance in this here enterprise.
你记得去年春天
You remember last spring when
你想带我去Harlem Park吗
you tried to take me up to Harlem Park?
他们都找不到我的档案 Bubs
They couldn't even find my records, Bubs.
他们一点都不想管我
They didn't want shit to do with me.
但他们给你安排了班级 对不对
They put you in a classroom, right?
老师都没有看过我一眼
The teacher didn't look at me once.
所以你退学了
So you rolled out.
而谁又因此受伤了
An' who got hurt behind that, huh?
是老师还是你
The teacher or you?
4乘以5加上6乘以7是多少
What's four times five plus six times seven?
你瞧 你瞧
See? See?
管他的 我等不及要开学了
Fuck that shit, son. I can't wait until school starts.
- 你开玩笑吧 - 不 说真的 小子
- You joking, right? - Nah, seriously, son.
我等不及要看那些妞儿们
I can't wait to see all them girls,
看看有没有人暑假变胖了
see which ones got phat over the summer,
- 你知道吗 - 猜我上个礼拜看到谁了
- you know? - Guess who I saw last week?
- 谁?
- Kwaneese Davis - Who? - Kwaneese Davis.
哦 你是说 翘臀Kwaneese?
Oh, shit, you mean Cute-Ass Kwaneese?
- 没错 - 她胖了吗
- Uh-huh. - She phat?
咪咪也大了
Got titties, too.
我绝对要搞到这个妞 你们看着吧
I'm definitely tappin' that pussy, now, y'all watch.
我今年会围着Kwaneese转
I'm be all up in Kwaneese this year
就像这样搞...
Iike this, bangin' that...
就好象你去年那样 对不对
Just like you tried to do last year, right?
去你的 黑佬 我才用了五分力
Fuck you, nigga, I only halfway tried.
那Michael今年你准备追谁
So, Michael, who you gettin' with this year?
憋屁股 叫什么来着 她叫什么
Stankin' ass, uh-- what's her name? What's her name?
- 她叫什么 - 哦 Tina
- What's her name? - Oh, Tina.
Tina  Tina Jenkins Tina-- Tina Jenkins.
别说Tina的坏话
Don't talk bad about Tina, man.
那不是坏话
I'm not sayin' that it bad.
我只是说她在男生更衣室里
I'm sayin' she be sucking dudes' dicks
给大伙儿吹箫罢了
in the boys' bathroom and shit,
- 仅此而已 - 我明白了
- that's all. - I heard you, man.
她吹的比你还好 Namond
She suck dick even better than you do, Namond.
- 哦 - 哇
- Oh! - Wow.
怎么 怎么
What up? What up, see?
打得好
Good jabbin', man.
停手 停手 别扯坏了这衣服
Chill chill chill! Don't rip this shit.
才刚买的
I just bought this throwback.
喂 Michael 要是换一件衣服
Yo, Michael, son, if I ain't had this shit on,
我早把你揍扁了 我认真的
I'd have fucked you up. Word up.
你们这些小黑佬没事干吗
You little niggas ain't up to no good, is you?
喂 怎么了 Monk
Yo, what up, Monk?
马上要开学了 对吗
Look here, first day of school coming up, right?
- 对 下周 - 你们新衣服什么的都买了吗
- Yeah, next week. - Y'all need school clothes and shit?
给
Here...
哇 为什么给我啊
Yo, what's this for?
怎么 没听见吗 买新衣服
What, you ain't hear me? For new clothes,
还有其他你们需要的
whatever else you need to get.
- 谢了 老兄 - 操 200?
- Thanks, man! - Damn, 200?
- 哇 谢了 Monk - 你们要谢谢我的兄弟Marlo
- Yo, thanks, Monk. - Oh, you need to thank my man Marlo.
他不想你们这群小混蛋
He ain't wanna see you little motherfuckers
开学第一天就邋邋遢遢的
going raggedy on the first day.
哇 那就是Marlo?
Whoa. That Marlo?
- 不用了 谢谢 - 你什么都不用做
- Naw, man, no thanks. - You ain't gotta do nothing for it.
不 谢了
No thank you, man.
嘿 Monk先生
Hey, yo, Mr. Monk?
如果他不要给我就好了
I'll take his if he don't want it.
- 我给他留着 - 喂 别贪心
- I'll hold his for you-- - Yo, don't press, man.
别贪心
Don't press.
你哪根筋搭错了 小子
Fuck is wrong with you, boy?
看不上我的钱么
You too good for my money?
还是你这个操蛋的小愤青
Or is you such a bitch-ass punk
担心我的钱不干净?
you worried about where my money come from?
好吧
Yeah.
没事了 小子
Ain't no thing, shorty.
没事
We cool.
你谁都不能告诉
You can't tell nobody.
发誓你不会传出去
Swear to me you won't spread this around.
他看到你了吗
And he saw you?
对 他看到我了
Yeah, he saw me.
Carv 我这次只怕是自身难保了
Carv, I'm fucked in the ass with a pineapple on this.
- 你对他说什么了 - 我说 "市长先生
- What the helI'd you say to him? - I said, "Mr. Mayor,
您的鸡巴真是又粗又长啊
that's a good, strong dick you got there,
依小人之见您也知道该怎么用好它"
and I see you know how to use it."
我啥都没说!
I didn't say shit!
我也没等到他说话 就出来了
And I didn't wait for him to say anything, either.
操 我这辈子是升不了职了
Shit, I'm never gonna make rank now.
他们会把我调去开船或是什么的 好像McNulty那样
I'll end up riding the boat or some shit like McNulty.
这可不是我能管的事情啊
This is way beyond my pay grade.
我们得找懂政策的人
We need to get with someone who knows politics.
我们认识这样的人么
Who do we know like that?
犯罪问题上 他知道你会追问
On crime, he knows you're coming,
所以他会设置一些陷阱
so he's gonna set some traps
然后着重在数据上 显示犯罪率下降了
and lean on stats that say crime is down.
同时他会用贬低你的方式
He'll also try to inoculate himself
来抬高自己
by making it about you.
比如要是你提起毒品和暴力犯罪
Like you're playing the race card
你就是搞种族主义
if you talk about drugs or violent crime.
他希望能把你打压下去
He's hoping you'll back down.
但你却要双倍返还
But you come on twice as hard:
"Clarence Royce没有保证 我们城市的安全"
"Clarence Royce has not made this city safe."
嘿 Jen 怎么了
Hey, Jen, what's up?
- 你有空吗 - 我有空 怎么了
- You got a second? - No, I got time, what is it?
- 你忘了付支票 - 哦 不 不是吧
- You forgot the check. - Oh no, you're kidding me.
你必须马上去付
You've got to pay it right away.
不 不 我这儿就有号码
No, no, I got the number here, yeah.
我马上处理好
No, I'll straighten it out straightaway.
- 好的 - 好
- Okay. - Yeah.
糟糕
Shit.
我忘了把支票
I forgot to mail the check
寄给教区去了
to the fuckin' archdiocese.
要是我处理不好
My kid's gonna get tossed outta St. Albans
他们就要把我的孩子踢出圣Albans学校
if I don't get my shit together.
Tommy 集中注意力了
Tommy. Focus.
他用种族和扯淡的犯罪数据来对付我
He comes at me with race and some bullshit crime stats.
我要忽视种族问题
I ignore the race thing and counter by noting
然后提出虽然其他暴力犯罪的发生率 降低到了12%
that homicides are up 15% even though
但谋杀罪却上升到了15%
other violent crime stats are down 12%.
我指出 除非是Royce从中作梗
I point out this does not make sense
将其他诸如抢劫 强奸 和伤害罪的数据
unless Royce is cooking the crime stats,
统统抹杀掉 否则说不通
making robberies, rapes, and assaults disappear.
我暗示市长并没有诚实地交代 犯罪率问题
I suggest the mayor is not telling the truth about crime in the city.
我最后总结到
I conclude by declaring that it is for all of Baltimore--
我将公众安全
every neighborhood--
整个巴尔的摩 每个社区的安全
that I'm making public safety
视为我竞选的基石
the cornerstone of my campaign.
明晚 我会好好让他出出丑
Tomorrow night, I will kick his ass.
但第二天清晨
But the next morning,
我却依然以白人的身份 苏醒于一个黑人城市中
I still wake up white in a city that ain't.
Theresa修女吗
Sister Theresa?
嘿 你好
Hey, how you doing?
对 Tommy Carcetti
Yeah, Tommy Carcetti.
喂 Randy 你吓死我了
Yo, Randy, man, you crack me up, son.
追着他说
Running behind him talking about,
"他不要我要 Monk先生 把他的钱给我"
"I'll take his, Mr. Monk. Give his to me."
听着 兄弟 我需要钱啊
Listen, man, I could've used that extra.
我已经把Anna小姐给我买衣服的钱
I already spent all the clothes money
花在给学校补货上面了
Miss Anna gave me on stuff to sell at school.
而且Marlo想给我们
Yo, and plus Marlo wanted us to have it.
他想要告诉我们
He want to show us
这里谁是老大哥
who callin' the shots out here.
- 喂 Michael 你干嘛不要? - 我不能那样
- Yo, Michael, why you ain't take it? - that ain't me, man.
- 什么 - 欠黑佬的人情
- Say what? - That owin' niggas for shit, man.
- 我不要 - 随便谁给我钱
- That ain't me. - I'll take any motherfuckin' money
- 我都会要 - 为什么?
- if he givin' it away now. - Why?
你们家是我们这群人里最有钱的
Shit, your family got more money than all of us.
对 但我妈说了她不会给我钱的
Yeah, but my mom said she cuttin' me off,
她也不给我买新衣服什么的
she ain't buyin' me school clothes and shit.
我在Bodie那儿的工作也给你了 所以...
You already took my job with Bodie, so...
- 先生们 - 哦 我的天
- Gentlemen. - Oh my God.
我操
Oh shit!
- Donut 你这个疯子 - 喂 Donut
- Donut, you crazy, man. - Yo, Donut.
你能给我们偷一辆露营车么
You think you could steal us one of them camper trucks?
要是你偷来一辆露营车 我们就可以
Yo, you steal us a camper truck, we can all go campin'
- 去森林里露营了 - 我害怕森林
- out in the woods an' all. - I be scared in the woods.
我不是说那么远 就是Howard县那儿
I don't mean far like that. I mean like Howard County.
不行 不行
Naw naw naw, man.
三K党住在Howard县
The Ku Klux Klan live in Howard County.
我确定
I know that for a fact.
黑佬 我大姨住在Howard县
Nigga, my aunt live in Howard County.
那儿没三K党
There ain't no Ku Klux Klan there.
黑佬 你太单纯了
Nigga, you simple, I swear.
嘿 喂 Donut 开车
Hey, yo, Donut, drive me away
别理这群无知的贱人
from these ignorant bitches, man.
我跟这群黑佬讲不下去了
You can't tell these niggas nothin'.
闪开点 杂碎
Move, motherfucker.
你看得到方向盘后面吧
Can you see over the steering wheel?
你觉得他会跟我谈吗
You think he'll talk to me?
实在不行就报我的名字
Use my name if you have to.
我在他部门做了8个月
I had one of his sectors for eight months.
这是怎么搞的
What's wrong with that picture?
黑佬 要是停车场里有黑色的
Nigga, if there was a black one in the parking lot,
我就会偷黑的了
I would've took one.
喂 缉毒组 缉毒组!
Yo-- narcos, narcos!
760呼叫K-G-A
760 to K-G-A.
需要紧急援助 Calhoun和Mosher路口
I got a bailout at Calhoun and Mosher,
6至8名未成年人
six to eight juveniles beating feet north
正跑向Calhoun北面的小巷里
in the alleys around Calhoun.
10-4 K-G-A呼叫所有小组--
10-4. K-G-A to all units--
我超爱这个 就好象以前一样
I love this. Just like old times.
我没必要追那群小混蛋
I don't need to chase these fucking knuckleheads.
一半的我都认识
I know half of 'em.
操 我知道他们聚在哪儿玩
Shit, I know where they hang.
而且 你穿的有些夸张
Besides, you're a little overdressed.
我们报告了 然后你就去见那个人谈事吧
Let's just call this in and go see the man about your thing.
喂喂 老兄 我啥都没做
Yo, yo, man, I ain't do nothin'!
- 我什么都没做! - 那你为什么跑
- I ain't do nothin'! - Then why you runnin'?
- 因为你在追啊 - 对 你叫什么
- 'Cause you chasin' me. - Yeah, right. What's your name?
- 真的 我什么都没做 - 你他妈叫什么
- For real, man, I ain't do nothin'. - What's your goddamn name?
- Randy 什么
- Randy - Randy. - Randy what?
- 我知道你没撒谎
- Wagstaff - Wagstaff. - I know you ain't lying.
没人会编出这种烂名字
Wouldn't nobody make that shit up.
把手扶墙上
Put your hands against this fucking wall.
快 你知不知道
Come on-- what do you know
有跑腿的弃了赃车?
about hoppers bailing from a stolen car?
不知道
Nothin'.
小混蛋 你骗人
Little motherfucker. You slingin'.
- 不 长官 我没有 - 你还他妈没有
- No, sir. I swear to God. - Hell you ain't.
不然你怎么揣着200美金到处跑
How else you walking around with 200 in your pocket?
我养母给我的 买上学衣服
My foster mother gave me that to buy school clothes with.
你养母给了你200现金?
Your foster mother gave you 200 cash?
对
Yeah.
让她来西部警局
Tell her to come down to the Western,
我到时候还给她
and I'll give it back to her.
快滚 混蛋 别逼我抓你
Beat feet, motherfucker, before I lock your little ass up.
看着我干什么 滚
Don't be fucking lookin' at me, move.
这个 可是猛料啊
This right here is fire.
也就是说 我准备自己和他们对着干
That said, I'm ready to serve 'em myself
你们的名字不会被记录
and keep your names off the returns.
我已经退休了
I've got my 20.
你们俩还得留在这个部门里
You two got to live in this department.
管他呢 他们住哪儿
Fuck 'em where they live.
走了
Let's go.
钢铁的价格还是那样
The price of steel being what it is,
要是我们没法处理超出的部分
that's gonna kill us if we can't
我们就死定了
pass along the overage.
Krawczyk先生吗 巴尔的摩警察
Mr. Krawczyk? Baltimore City Police.
- 这是什么 - 询问传票
- What's this? - A subpoena for records.
你现在就需要吗
You need these right now, because, uh,
我今天有点忙
I'm kinda up to my ass in stuff today.
还是准时着来吧
Honor it in a timely fashion.
这是法律规定的
I think that's the legal standard.
- 没问题 警探...
- Shakima Greggs - No problem, Detective-- - Shakima Greggs.
你是市区的警察吗
You're with the city?
- 哪个组的 - 重案组
- Which unit? - Major Crimes.
参议员
Senator.
这他妈是什么
What the hell is this?
询问传票
Subpoena for records.
斯芬克斯俱乐部的吗
Sphinx Club?
- 年度最佳 - 这他妈扯什么淡呢
- Man of the year. - What kinda bullshit is this?
你们这群家伙肯定是疯了
You people must be out your damn mind.
你参加过斯芬克斯俱乐部吗
You were in the Sphinx Club?
我叔叔以前是那儿的酒保
My uncle used to tend bar over there.
Marvin Thompson 矮个子
Marvin Thompson? Short guy--
你叫什么名字 警员
What is your name, Officer?
Sydnor警探 先生
Detective Sydnor, sir.
"重案组"?
"Major Crimes"?
操了...
Shit...
过得愉快 先生
Enjoy your day, sir.
孩子 我们走着瞧
Son, we're gonna see about this.
就这样吧
That's it.
干了那婊子
Yankin' that bitch.
小子 用力点不对
Son, that's too much knuckle.
你他妈你一直打电话给我干吗
Why the fuck you keep callin' me?
但我说什么了
But what I say, though?
他收到信息了 傻子
He got the message, fool.
喂 Monk 是谁
Yo, Monk. Who that, man?
Andre 老熟人Andre
Andre. Old Face Andre.
来 让我跟他打招呼
Here, let me holla at that dude.
喂 听好了 兄弟
Yo, check this out, man.
我来给你们示范下
I'm gonna show you how you do this
怎么才好
right here, man.
别他妈催我
Don't rush me on shit.
到时候我自然会来找你
I'll get at you when I'm at you.
喂 记得你在和谁说话
Yo, remember who you're talking to
别再乱说话
before you say another fuckin' word.
Andre 兄弟
Andre, man.
这黑佬比我俩孩子他妈还要烦人
Nigga need more maintenance than both my babies' mamas.
意外 这是一场意外
By accident. It was accidental.
市长什么都没说吗
And the mayor doesn't say anything?
我猜他是挺生气的
I think he's pretty mad.
我是说 警司长 我跟你来谈
I mean, Major, I only took this detail
只是因为我想要升警司
to try and make sergeant on this list.
孩子 你已经要升警司了
Kid, you made sergeant already.
如果Royce连任了
Shit, if Royce gets reelected,
两年内你就是警督 四年你就能当警司了
you'll be a lieutenant in two years and a major in four.
你回市政厅去
You go back down to the hall.
假装什么都没看到
You act like it never happened.
闭上嘴
You shut up.
不要对任何人说
Say nothing to no one.
但是市长 他会...
But the mayor, he's gonna--
他会看着你 看你这么对待这件事
He's gonna watch and see how you carry it.
孩子 你就是块硬石头
And kid, you're a fucking rock.
市长看着你的时候
When the mayor looks in your face,
他知道这件事可以信任你
he knows he can trust you with this.
我打赌 过几个星期
And I'll bet in a couple of weeks,
他会非常亲切地问你
he comes asking, real friendly-like,
你想在这个部门里做什么职位
what are you looking to do with the department?
你对职业有什么规划
With your career?
他会对你感兴趣
He's interested in you.
但他不会提到吹箫
But he doesn't mention no blowjob,
你也不会提
and neither do you.
这件事就静静地搁置在那里
Uh-uh, it just lays there
就好像盘子里的一个坏掉的饺子
Iike a bad pierogi on the plate,
大家都假装它不存在
both of you pretending it ain't there.
万一他整我怎么办
What if he screws me over?
把我换到了午夜班
Bounces me to a midnight shift?
他要这么做 你就捅出去
He does that, you will talk.
我现在真想变成你啊
What I wouldn't give to be in your shoes right now.
孩子 现在升职
Kid, careers have been launched
可比以前慢多了
on a hell of a lot less.
闭嘴装傻就好了
Just shut up and play dumb.
我能做到的 没问题
I can do that. No problem.
谢谢 警司长
Thanks, Major.
谢谢你能花时间陪我谈这件事
Thanks for taking the time to meet me on this.
我是说 跟你谈过之后 我如释重负
I mean, it's a weight off my mind talking to you.
真的
It really is.
不客气
Don't mention it.
说不定等你升职了
Maybe you get a chance to do me a turn
我还等你还我人情呢
one day after you make rank, huh?
天哪
Oh, boy.
没事了 Carv
It's all good, Carv.
如果是联邦下来的混球
Because if some federal motherfucker comes
我还能对他们说" 嘿
through the door, I say, "Hey,
一切都好"
it's all in the game."
但一个市级的警察?
But a City Police?
巴尔的摩市警察? 滚一边去吧
Baltimore City? Hell, no.
完全不可能 因为我知道
Can't be happenin', 'cause I know
我给市长还有他的选票
I have raised too much goddamn money
募集了多少资金
for the mayor and his ticket.
滚一边去吧
Hell, no!
这世上还有没有感恩之心啊
Ain't no soul in the world
那狗日的一点都不知回报
that fuckin' ungrateful!
- 冷静点 Clay - 洗钱吗
- Calm down, Clay, hmm? - Money laundering?
他们想跟我谈谈
They gonna come talk to me
洗钱的事情?
about money laundering?
在西巴尔的摩吗
In West Baltimore:
操 你们觉得我都是从哪儿
Shit... Where do y'all think I'm gonna
募集到资金给你们拉选票的?
raise cash for the whole damn ticket?
从自助洗衣店里吗
From laundromats and shit?
从小屁股的朝鲜人开的杂货铺里吗
From some tiny-ass Korean groceries?
你觉得我闲着没事干
You think I have time to ask a man
问人家干嘛给我钱吗
why he givin' me money?
或者是他这钱从哪儿来?
Or where he gets his money from?
给我的钱 我当然就收了
I'll take any motherfucker's money if he givin' it away.
- 我不想知道 - 我知道你不想知道
- I don't wanna know. - I know you don't wanna know.
但我做牛做马
But I'm scratchin' an' clawin'
都是为了你 Clarence
to get it done for you, Clarence.
为了你 还有我 还有队伍里的其他人
For you and me and the rest of the team.
但最后居然是
And who comes through my door
巴尔的摩的警察
but a Baltimore City Police
来我这儿想要给我找茬
Iookin' to get up into my shit about it.
Clay 我都不知道这回事
Clay, we didn't know about that.
抱歉 我得走了
I'm sorry, I gots to leave up out of here
不然我要发狂了
before I lose my damn mind.
大家都不知道
Nobody knew about that.
你想烧我的钱
You want to run a campaign
来支持你的竞选
with my money pillowed under your ass,
你总得让你的人 他妈的配合一下吧 Clarence
you need your people to back the fuck up, Clarence.
Krawczyk在1线上
Krawczyk's on line one.
我去找Burrell和Demper
I'll jump on Burrell and Demper both.
看看到底是怎么回事
Find out what the hell's going on.
等等
Wait-- wait a minute.
那个新的司机 光头的 白人
That new driver, the bald-headed, white kid.
他是哪儿来的
Where did he come here from?
Hoskins带他来的
Hoskins brought him in, I think.
Hoskins 他的部门里
Hoskins: He doesn't have a better rabbi
没有更好的人选吗
in the department than that:
怎么 你想开掉他吗
Why, you want to lose him?
我再想想
Let me think about it.
对 Walker警官就是那种货色
Yeah, man, Officer Walker be shady like that.
警察也偷
Police be stealin', yo.
我最想要一辆Caprice
Yo, what I really wanna get is a bubble Caprice.
我也见到过一辆好的了
I seen a nice one, too.
94年的Caprice 22号街上的 那车真是靓啊
'94 caprice on 22's. Shit was tight.
你还是小心点吧 他们今天差点抓住你
You better be careful. They almost caught you today.
黑佬 他们才没有差点抓到我
Nigga, they ain't almost caught shit.
嘘 都安静点
Shh. Be quiet, y'all.
你们都知道我是谁吧
Y'all know who I am, right?
Carver 缉毒组的
Carver. You a narcos.
今天我是偷车组的
Today I'm auto theft.
善意的警告
Fair warning.
如果再让我看到你们这些小杂碎
If I see any of y'all little hoppers
哪怕是朝着汽车笑一下
even smile at a motor vehicle again,
就不会有少年犯听证会 只有我的人
it ain't gonna be no juvenile hearing. No, it's gonna be my people
同你们在巷子里解决 听懂了吗
settlin' up with y'all in the alleys. You understand?
- 喂 你不能这么做的 - 你试试 Namond
- You can't do that, yo. - Try me, Namond.
对 没错 我知道你们的名字
Yeah, that's right. I know your name,
我知道你们住在哪儿
I know where you live
我也知道你们玩在哪儿
and I know where y'all hang.
我靠啊 车真不错
Damn, yo! Nice ride.
- 嘿 Bunk - 嗯?
- Hey, Bunk. - Hmm?
找到你那枪手了不
You have any luck finding your shooter?
没 还逃着呢
Naw. He's runnin'.
但至少我知道枪手是谁
But at least I know who my shooter is, right?
我只要找到那小子就好
I just got to find the boy.
- 家人还不肯开口吗 - 对
- Family won't go for nothin'? - Nah.
当妈的一句话不说
Mother wouldn't say shit.
但又不是一般妈妈撒谎的方式
But it wasn't the usual way a mama lies.
- 你什么意思 - 我也不知道
- What do you mean? - I don't know.
一种奇怪的感觉
It was a weird vibe, man.
我没法解释
I can't explain it.
感觉好像她在神游一样
It was like she was off somewhere else in her head.
四号线 接啊
Line four. Communication.
- 该谁了 - 到我了 我来接
- Who's up? - I'm up. I'll take it.
不 等等
No, wait.
如果是你接 你这走运的家伙
If it's yours, you lucky bitch,
一定是室内家暴 有四个证人
then it's a domestic in a house with four wits.
- 你要接么 - 但如果我接了
- You want the call? - But I pick up that phone,
是不是就没运气了
do I make it unlucky?
还是说这还算是你接的
Or is it still your call?
你要接就接呗
You want the call, pick it up.
不接拉倒
If you don't, don't.
凶杀组 Norris
Homicide. Norris.
好的 嗯 我知道了
Right. Uh-huh. I got it.
Lanvale街1400号 街头凶杀 被邮差发现的
1400 Lanvale, in the street, found by the post officer,
没有嫌犯 没有证人
no suspects, no witnesses.
啊 兄弟
Ah, man.
牛逼不如狗屎运啊
Better to be lucky than to be good.
你想用重沙包吗
You wanna work the heavy bag?
行 给你四轮
G'head. Four rounds.
嘿
Hey.
- 嘿 - 我叫Gail
- Hey. - I'm Gail.
我给你还有其他人做了这个
I made this for you and the other men
以表达我的谢意
to let you know you're appreciated.
- 真不错 - 桃子馅饼
- That's real nice. - Peach cobbler.
抱歉 我忘了你是谁的妈妈?
I'm sorry, I forgot whose mother you are.
哦 我没有儿子
Oh, I don't have any boys.
我只是很欣赏你的做法
I just appreciate what you been doing,
你和那些教练们志愿做这些
you and the other coaches volunteering and all.
谢谢 你人很不错
Well, thank you, that's real nice.
我有三个女儿 你们不教女孩的 对吗
I got three girls. Y'all don't teach girls, though, do you?
- 不 这方面我还是很老派的 - 哦 我同意
- No, I'm real old-fashioned about that. - Oh, I agree wit' you.
男人有男人的样子 女人有女人的样子
Men should be men and women should be women.
我就是这么想的
That's what I think.
一击致命 背部上方 没找到弹壳
Single wound, upper back, no casings,
没有目击证人 搜查也没有结果
no witnesses, and nothing on the canvas.
- 你到的时候就死了 - 也没死透
- Dead when you got here? - Actually not.
我到的时候他还清醒着 在吐血
He was still conscious and coughin' blood when I pulled up.
- 你问了是谁开枪的吗 - 对 我问了是谁开的枪
- You ask who shot him? - Yeah, I asked who shot him.
他说是一个拿枪的人
He said it was a guy with a gun.
喂 你他妈一直给我打电话干吗
Yo, why the fuck you keep calling me?
他有消息 傻瓜
He got the message, fool.
喂 Monk 那家伙是谁
Yo, Monk, who that, man?
Andre 老熟人Andre
Andre. Old Face Andre.
喂 Monk 那家伙是谁
Yo, Monk, who that, man?
Andre 老熟人Andre
Andre. Old Face Andre.
注意听这儿
Lemme key that.
喂 Monk 那家伙是谁
Yo, Monk. Who that, man?
Andre 老熟人Andre
Andre. Old Face Andre.
喂 看看这儿
Yo, check this out, man.
别为了这点破事催我
Don't rush me on shit.
- 到时候我自然会来找你 - 我只是说...
- I'll get at you when I'm at you. - I'm just saying...
老熟人Andre
Old Face Andre.
想跟Monk Metcalf补货
Tryin' to reup with Monk Metcalf.
对 Monk在自己的手机上接的电话
Yeah, well, Monk took the call on his cell phone.
但第二个声音却超过了他
But that second voice ranked him.
从听上去看 是超过了所有人的声音
Ranked everybody, by the sound of it.
Marlo Stanfield 在接电话
Marlo Stanfield. On the phone.
他冲着电话吼的样子 要我说 就是他
The way he shut that call down, I'd say, yeah, that was him.
对 但背景是什么声音 烟火还是...
Yeah, but what was all that in the background? Fireworks, or--
不 间隔很有规律 应该是半自动手枪
Naw, it was regular intervals. Semi-auto from the sound.
也许是射击训练
Target practice, maybe.
要么就是一个射击班
Either that or a firing squad.
这家伙几个月没有人命案子了
There are no bodies on this guy in months,
但他在接电话
but we get him on the phone
接电话的地方又听起来像是在打仗
and it sounds like a war zone.
至少他还在时不时接电话
Well, at least he gets on a phone now and then.
- 也是一条线索 - 他口气真大 是不是
- That's something. - Sounds arrogant, doesn't he?
感觉像是个万物之王
Like he's the lil' king of everything.
啊 年轻人
Ah. Youth.
喂 老兄
Yo, bubs.
我还以为你睡着了
Thought you asleep.
如果你觉得好
If you want...
我可以去上学
I could go to school some.
我休学了挺长一阵子的
I ain't been for a while,
所以我也不知道我能不能上学
so I don't even know if I can.
但如果你想要我去
But if you want me to go...
也不是问题
ain't no thing.
法官大人气疯了
His Honor was mad:
我都形容不出
I can't begin to describe it.
- 他想要怎么样 - 把那张传票拦下来
- What's he want from us? - To block the subpoenas,
但他知道我们做不到 因为传票已经发出去的
but he knows we can't once those things go out.
我所能承诺他的
What I could promise him
只是我们这儿不再给他出意外
is no more surprises out of our shop.
是McNulty这混球搞的鬼么
Is this that cocksucker McNulty?
这次不是 他已经从那个组调离一年了
Not this time. He's been gone from that unit a year.
我猜最有可能的是Lester Freamon
My best guess would be Lester Freamon.
- Lester可会玩着呢
- Freamon? - Freamon? - Lester's got a helluva game.
那我们得好好治治这混帐东西
Well, we need to sit on the motherfucker.
局长 那个组
All that unit needs, Commissioner,
只需要好好监管就可以了
is proper supervision.
嘿 马里兰州
Hey, the State of Maryland
刚刚又失去了一名肯合作的证人
just lost another cooperating witness,
而我也省了很多加班时间
and I just found a lot of fucking overtime.
这件案子从"管他妈是谁"的毒品谋杀
This case went from a who-gives-a-fuck drug murder
一下就上了快车道
to straight-up red ball.
操 我真该接那个电话
Fuck, I should've picked up that phone.
嘿 队长 我那受害人是个证人
Hey, Sarge. My boy's a witness.
18部正在处理的毒品案子的证人
Drug case pending in part 18.
你确定他是因此被杀的吗
You know for sure he's killed for that reason?
不知道 但从法院电脑的记录来看
Don't know shit. But from the look of the court computer,
这家伙是检方手上唯一的牌了
this guy's the state's whole case.
别告诉媒体受害者是证人
Don't put it in the 24 that the guy was a witness.
相信我 现在是选举年
Trust me, we do not wanna kick shit
我们可不能出什么岔子 继续调查 抓牢吸毒过度这条线
in an election year. Work the case, take the O.T.,
在确定之前都不要提起那是个证人
but bury the witness angle till we know for sure.
带上门
And close the door.
对
Yeah.
我是Landsman 凶杀组的
It's Landsman. Homicide.
今早市长在么
Is the major in this morning?
下一条 班级纪律
Next order of business: class rules.
我们组的人保持一致最有效
It helps if the team is constant on these.
别给孩子们太多自由空间
Less wiggle room for the children.
Scott女士
Mrs. Scott:
和去年一样 双倍行距
Same as last year, double space.
语言艺术 我们批了很多论文
Language Arts, we grade a lot of papers.
虽然没有让他们写得更好些
It doesn't make them write any better,
但我看着省力多了
but it saves my eyesight.
记得要给他们示范明白
Make sure you demonstrate it for them.
有些人觉得双倍行距 是可以在单词之间多点空格
Some of them think double-space means more space between words.
我觉得八年级的学生
I'd of thought by eighth grade--
首要规则 Pryzbylewski先生 别假设
Rule of thumb around here, Mr. Pryzbylewski: Never assume.
你想让他们做什么 就解释清楚
Explain what you want them to do,
让他们做一次 然后再解释一次
have them do it, then explain again.
耐心操练之后 他们就明白了
With time and patience, they'll get it.
- Shapiro女士 - 如果我们都用同样的抬头
- Mrs. Shapiro: - It's easier to keep track of lab work
那跟踪实验室报告就简单多了
if we all use the same heading.
右上角 在第一条蓝线上方
Upper right-hand corner, above the first blue line:
名字 日期 班级号 是这个顺序吗
name, date, and class number, in that order?
Pryzbylewski先生 你有什么想要说的吗
Mr. Pryzbylewski, do you have anything you want addressed?
能让他们不嚼口香糖么
Can we have them not chew gum?
在Smapson女士的课堂他们就不嚼
They won't do it in Ms. Sampson's class,
但我花了4年 也没有办法阻止他们
but in four years, I have not been able to stop them.
你可以试试 但第一年 还是以基本的规则为主
You can try, but first year, it's best to stick with basics.
我们组里的原则是 只有所有人都能做到的
And team rules-- we can only go
我们才记录在原则里
with what we can all enforce.
还有 记得关窗
Also, keep your windows closed.
让他们犯困 犯困是好事
Makes them drowsy, and drowsy's good.
还有很多要学的 但现在
There's a lot to learn. But for now,
在教学计划里加上很多的活动
build in lots of activities in your lesson plan.
再怎么多也不为过
You can't have enough.
他们忙起来就不会提防你了
You keep them busy, you keep them off-guard.
你的眼神要柔和些
You need soft eyes.
什么?
Excuse me:
对 但这样你还是得用你老婆的名字
Yeah, but that doesn't prevent you
给更多的钱
from giving more under your wife's name,
如果你孩子用的是分开的帐号 那就更多了
your children, if they got separate accounts...
对
yeah.
抱歉 Richie 你先别挂啊
Sorry, Richie, can you hold a moment?
你那警察公会的兄弟
Your buddy from the F.O.P.
说有要紧的事情
And he says it's important.
嘿 Stan
Hey, Stan.
我这儿有场选举要输 忙着哟
I'm a little busy losing an election here.
你记得不 六个月前
You remember about six months ago,
你告诉我要注意
you told me to keep an eye for
有没有证人被杀的消息
any witnesses gettin' clipped?
你还记得不
You remember that?
谁比我更在行呢 Tommy
Who's better than me, Tommy?
嘿 Richie 我等会儿给你回电
Hey, Richie, can I call you back?
谢了
Thanks.
你还需要我做什么吗 Donnelly小姐
Anything else you want me to do, Miss Donnelly?
呃...
Uh...
你住在Duquan Weems家附近 对吗
you live near Duquan Weems, correct?
Dukie?
你把这个带给他吧
I want you to take this to his house.
这些衣服干净不了多久的
These clothes won't stay clean long.
保证得把它们直接给Duquan
Make sure you deliver them just to Duquan,
而不是那栋房子里的大人
not any of the adults in the house.
- 直接给Duquan - 今晚就送吗
- Just Duquan. - Want me to do it tonight?
那再好不过了 还有 Crystal 今天就到这里了 谢谢
that would be great. And, Crystal, thanks for today.
不客气 Donnelly小姐
You're welcome, Miss Donnelly.
- 有什么事吗 - 是这样的 夫人
- Can I help you? - Yes, ma'am.
这位年轻人来注册上学
This young man has to be registered for school.
- 他之前来上过学吗 - 他应该来得
- Does he attend here: - He should.
我是说 你去年是几年级 亲爱的?
What I mean is, what grade were you in last year, dear?
他之前走上了歧路
He kinda lost his way some time ago.
现在他同我住一起
He's livin' with me now.
而你是他的...
And you are his...
叔叔 我是他叔叔
Uncle. I'm his uncle.
来我的办公室吧
Come into my office.
谢谢 借过
Thank you. Excuse me.
喂 瞧瞧教练风流着呢
Yo, look at coach workin' it, yo.
好了 休息下 打得真好
A'ight, man, break. That's what I like to see, baby.
打得真是好 不过你得多用用左手
That's what I like to see. You gotta use that left
- 知道了不 - 喂 兄弟 完事了么
- a little more, though, a'ight? - Yo, man, you finished?
- 过两分钟再来一轮 - 得了吧 我马上要比赛了
- Got another two minutes. - Fuck that, I got a fight coming up.
你过会儿再来 行不
You can come back later, a'ight?
喂 我兄弟说了还有一轮 听到了没
Yo, man said he got one more round, a'ight?
一边去 小崽子
Step aside, youngin'.
别这样 我可以用四轮沙包
Naw, man, bag is mine for four rounds
- 我才打了三轮 - 去你的
- and I only did three. - Fuck that.
你他妈想干吗
What the fuck you tryin' to prove, huh?
哇 哇 别这样 住手 住手
Whoa, whoa. Come on, man, come on. Come on.
- 怎么了 小子们 - 我周六晚上有一场比赛
- What's going on, boy? - I got a fight Saturday night,
那小子不肯把沙包让出来
an' the boy won't get off the bag.
他没事占着沙包不放做什么
What the fuck he on the bag for anyway, huh?
他不打架 连吵架都不吵
He don't even fight. He don't even spar.
想吵哥随时奉陪
Spar with your ass any day.
- 那就来啊 - 嘿 嘿 嘿
- Come on, then. - Hey hey hey.
都住手 听到了么
Y'all be cool, you hear me?
我不许你们做这种傻事
I ain't putting up with this foolishness.
过来 Michael
Come here, Michael.
- 我现在能用沙包了吗 - 不行 等等
- I can work the bag now, right? - Not yet. Just wait.
- 你说可以打四轮 - 对 我知道我说了什么
- You said four rounds. - Yeah, I know what I said.
你打完了就让Justin上
You finish up your rounds, and then Justin gets on.
我不想再听到你们吵架
I don't want hear no more street talk.
我们在这儿打拳击 不是打架
We boxin' up in here, we ain't fightin'.
他想要和我打一场
He wanna get in the ring with me,
- 我就陪他玩玩 - 看着我 看着我
- we can go. - Look here, look here,
我这么告诉你吧 你来这儿
Iet me tell you something: You can come here,
锻炼 使用器材
work out, use the equipment.
但只有受训练的人
But nobody gets in that ring
才可以进拳击场
unless they're being trained.
你想训练么
You wanna be trained?
你打沙包的时候我观察过你
I've been watching you hit that bag.
你是天生的右手选手
You got a natural right hand,
你出拳的方式 你击打的方式
the way you throw it, the way you land it.
如果要训练你的话
Now if I was to train you,
我们要从基本功开始
we'd have to start with floor work.
因为如果你不知道该怎么移动
'Cause see, if you don't know how to move,
你就甭想进那个拳击场了
you ain't got no business being in that ring.
你觉得呢
So what you think?
我想亲自训练你
I'd train you myself, personally.
不用了 我想现在这样就可以了
Nah, really I just wanna keep doing what I been doing.
好吗
All right.
瞧瞧这一拳
Let's see that right.
Uh-huh.
Dukie在家吗
Is Dukie here:
那是啥 是给Duquan的对吗
What's that? That's for Duquan, right?
我来拿给他
I take it to him.
给我
Gimme.
嘿 Crystal
Hey, Crystal.
Donnelly小姐要我把这些给你
Miss Donnelly said to give you these.
好 我马上下来
Okay. I'll be right down.
怎么
What?
若我的竞争对手要说
And for either of my opponents to suggest
市中心的发展建设资金是来源于
that downtown development comes at the expense
消减社区的资金
of our city's neighborhoods,
这实在是太不公平 也太不和谐了
well, that's just unfair and, uh, divisive.
他们又说我的管理
For them to suggest that my administration
是不作为的 那又...
has not been responsive, well...
经济发展不是一时半会儿的事情
Economic development cannot be a band-aid.
这是一个长期的过程 需要决心
It is a long-term process that requires commitment
需要重新教育我们的劳动力 并且 正如我之前所说
to retraining our workforce and, as I said before,
只有在这个城市
this can only be successful
让人们感觉安全的情况下 经济才能发展
in a city where people feel safe.
所以 在我们大谈经济发展
So before we can even begin to think about
将新兴工业引入巴尔的摩等等之前
Iuring new industries to Baltimore,
我们得想想 我们该怎么做
we need to think about how we can make
来让我们的社区和这个城市 重新变得安全
these neighborhoods and this city safe once again.
Carcetti先生也许觉得 煽动大家的恐怖情绪
Mr. Carcetti may think it's in his interest
对他有利
to exploit people's fears.
自从竞选开始他就对此乐此不疲
He's been doing it throughout this campaign.
我个人对这种做法十分不满
I'm offended by it, personally.
但事实是
But the fact is,
整个城市的暴力犯罪下降了
that violent crime is down citywide,
我们的警局工作非常努力
and our police department is working hard
来保证大家的安全
to keep it that way--
并且在我的管理之下 会继续保持如此
and will continue to do so under my administration.
Carcetti议员
Councilman Carcetti,
你有两分钟可以回答
you have two minutes to respond.
在座的各位 真的相信
Does anyone in this room really believe
巴尔的摩的犯罪率下降了吗
that crime is down in Baltimore?
你是说我是个骗子吗 Tommy
You calling me a liar, Tommy?
先生们 请不要做交流
Gentleman, please. No personal interactions.
- Carcetti议员 - 市长先生可否问心无愧地告诉
- Councilman Carcetti. - Can the mayor honestly tell
Rosemont 还有Belair Edison
the people of Rosemont, of Belair Edison,
还有Highlandtown 还有Cherry Hill的居民
of Highlandtown or Cherry Hill
毒品交易 暴力犯罪都下降了?
there's less drug-dealing, less violence?
任何警局提供的数据
Any statistics coming from the police department
都不可信 因为在这位市长的管理之下
cannot be trusted, because under this mayor,
警局更多考虑的是
the police are more concerned
如何保护Clarence Royce的政治目的 而非是同犯罪斗争
with protecting Clarence Royce politically than fighting crime.
没有领导可言 道德更是下降到了前所未有的低谷
There's no leadership and morale has never been lower.
我会改变这一切
I'll change that.
在市政厅这一切都惯例为之
It's business as usual down at City Hall
而结果就是 我们对犯罪的回应
and as a result, our response to crime
一次又一次地 显得
has been characterized time and time again
肆意无视
by wanton indifference.
...32码!
...32 yards!
我所说的惯例为之是何意
What do I mean by business as usual?
我所谓的肆意无视是何意
What do I mean by wanton indifference?
昨晚 在西巴尔的摩
Well, last night in West Baltimore,
Lanvale大街上
on Lanvale Street,
又有一名市民被枪击致死
another citizen was shot and killed.
这一次 被害者是一起将要开庭的
This time, the victim was a key witness
毒品案件的关键证人
in a drug case that had yet to come to court.
他非常勇敢地站出来
Courageously, this man had agreed to testify
将在两周之后为此案作证
in two weeks time in that case.
警察应该在保护他
The police should have been protecting him.
但他们没有 然后他被谋杀了
They were not, and he was murdered.
- 哦 糟糕 - 为什么 因为这位市长
- Oh, shit. - Why? Because this mayor...
到黄金时段了 Eddie
You're prime-time, Eddie.
不愿花钱保护他
...would not spend the money to protect him.
现在我完全相信
Now I have no doubt that in a moment or two
Clarence Royce会指责我
Clarence Royce will accuse me of exploiting
为了个人政治目的而挖掘 这人死亡的真相
this man's death for my own political purpose.
但事实是
But the truth is,
大约一年前 我给市长写了一封信
a year ago I wrote the mayor a letter.
我这儿有副本 想要的可以问我拿
I have copies for anyone who wants one.
我请求他 花一些钱
I begged him to spend the money
来加强对证人的保护
and make witness protection a priority.
他无视了我
He ignored me.
我甚至同立法机构的领导
I even teamed up with our legislative leaders--
Watkins代表及其他人一起
Delegate Watkins and others--
为在安纳波利斯通过的
to get matching funds for witness protection
证人保护法案募集资金
approved in Annapolis.
令人难以置信的是 这些募集起来的资金
And incredibly those matching funds
这个政府却从未向我们索要过
were never claimed by this administration.
现在提到这个也许是爆炸性的消息
Now to mention this now may be exploitive--
我不知道 我只知道这是真事
I don't know. I only know it's true,
正因其真实 我才恳请选民
and on such truths I ask the voters
为我们的城市 考虑是否该做出改变
of our city to consider a change.
各位 请暂时不要鼓掌了
Folks, please, please, hold your applause
请等到这轮提问结束之后鼓掌
until after the round of questions is over.
Royce市长?
Mayor Royce?
别再吓我们一跳了行不
No more surprises, huh:
我对Carcetti议员提到的那起案件
I am unaware of the specifics of the incident
并不很清楚
to which Councilman Carcetti is referring,
所以我无法直接回答这个问题
uh, so I can't answer that directly, um...
但我可以告诉大家 这座城市
however, I can say that this city places
将保护那些敢于出来作证的市民
the highest priority on protecting those citizens
视为头等大事
who come forward to testify,
而我们依然会继续如此
and we will continue to do so.
Carcetti先生说他曾给我写过一封信
Mr. Carcetti states that he wrote a letter
来表达他的担忧 我相信他的确写过
expressing his concerns, and I'm sure that he did.
我是说...
I mean it's-- it's--
写信当然简单
it's easy enough to write letters
你写完就完事了
when all you have to do is write letters.
但当你凭着
But when you are required
有限的资源
to run a city
来管理一座城市
on limited resources,
平衡各种利弊
and balance priorities,
那你就得明白
well, then-- well, then you understand
写信解决不了问题
that writing letters will not solve the problem.
哦 不行
Oh, no...
真要命 姑娘
Shit, girl.
你知道我总跟你站一边的
You know I'm-a roll wit' you.
呵 我也要休息一下的
Huh, I need some kinda break.
嗯嗯
Mm-hmm.
哦 我靠
Oh, shit.
真想看看那些个婊子
Ain't nothin' worse than them bitches
涂花了指甲来打二十一点
with fucked-up nails at the blackjack table.
你懂的
You know.
等一下
Hold on.
你觉得我儿子
You think my son gonna go up
会穿得灰头土脸地去学校么
to that school lookin' like himself?
我觉得 除非先整治好了学校
And I don't believe we can get a handle on crime
否则别谈什么整治犯罪
until we get a handle on the schools.
因为我们得在街头混混带坏这些孩子前
Because we need to be thinking about these kids
为他们做好打算
before the corners take them.
这意味着我们必须重新关注学校
And this means a renewed focus on our schools...